# **CECELIA FOWLER**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

203-598-6307

dev@ceceliafowler.com



ceceliafowler.com



www.linkedin.com/in/ceceliafowler



https://github.com/cecelia001

### **PROFILE**

Full Stack Developer with graduate level training in education and 4+ years managerial experience. Practical experience building applications from start to finish, including working with databases and APIs, performing unit testing, and implementing front-end frameworks. Lifelong learner with a diverse range of certifications and a strong desire to expand my skills.

### **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate** 2022

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain

Master of Science | Education

University of Bridgeport | Bridgeport, CT

2015

**Bachelor of Science | Education** 

2013

Western CT State University | Danbury, CT

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript Node.js

React/Vue Express

HTML/CSS MySQL

Bootstrap TDD/JEST

Advanced Git Postman

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Full Stack Developer** Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain

Developed 3 full stack apps featuring JavaScript, Node.js, React, MySQL, APIs, and more to demonstrate full stack proficiency and successful completion of a three-month intensive full-time bootcamp.

#### **Head of Youth Services** Feb 2018 - Sept 2022

Howard Whittemore & Terryville Library

Supervised and trained staff of 9 and 15 volunteers. Effectively managed budgets totaling \$15k. Fostered 6 new partnerships within the community. Boosted attendance of programs by 35%.

#### **Financial Consultant**

Jan 2016 - Feb 2018

AXA Advisors

Advised a total of \$6 AUM in retirement accounts. Drove 15+ qualified leads per week. Communicated regularly with over 130 clients, using Salesforce. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams.

### **Financial Consultant**

Aug 2013 - Jan 2016

AXA Advisors

Implemented positive and productive learning environment for 25+ children. Analyzed student performance and reported progress at weekly team meetings. Increased reading and math scores by 30%.

# **PROJECTS**

### **Roadtrip Social Planner**

December 2022

Built with: JavaScript, React, Node.is, Bootstrap, JSON Web Token, Bcrypt

Worked with an international team to create a full stack app with 3rd party API integration and authorization.

#### **Productivity Tracker**

November 2022

Built with: JSON Web Token, Bcrypt, JavaScript, React, MySQL, Chakra UI

Inherited legacy code to implement authentication and authorization, allowing for user registration and login.

#### **Monthly Expense Analysis**

October 2022

Built with: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, MySQL, REST APIs

Full stack app designed to monitor monthly expenses and establish personalized budgets for different categories.